<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Vosa Qobir</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Vosa Qobir</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 03:38:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/42654707-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/42654707-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>The United States is known for its liberality, which extends to aspects of government. The state has been the cornerstone to any form of political expression for the last four decades. Over the years, the United States has made remarkable achievements in human rights promotion. Mostly, this has been achieved through legislation that is strictly intended to protect freedoms. Hence, the US government, as well as a number of international bodies, have enjoyed various levels of success in human rights protection.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/71445412-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 12:56:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/71445412-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>Why do church consultations fail? Here's a story that demonstrates the one key reason why many churches get so excited about doing the work of consulting and then feel so disappointed when it doesn't seem to work.
It seemed like a good idea, particularly since the church's leadership team had just returned from a conference that was stimulating. They had been challenged by the speaker to start taking action in their church.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/40048205-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/40048205-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>Ask any human on Earth how he or she thinks the future will pan out, and you will get different answers. From predictions involving a worldwide human revolution to the Antichrist ruling the world, it is no surprise that different ideas have been proposed regarding the end times and what will occur during them.
While there are many different theories about the end days, perhaps one of the biggest questions we could ask is: How does the Bible tell us God’s end-times plan will play out for His creation?</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/66184794-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 17:39:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/66184794-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>This essay by Frederick C. Mather, taken from The Early Church in Jerusalem, was the starting point of my search for answers to the difficult questions that were coming before our churches at that time. I encourage you to read it carefully and attentively.
Our brother Frederick C. Mather made the following statement:
"If this citation be accurate, then there is a substantial difference between 'widow' as used here and its use in Acts 6:1.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/18505605-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 16:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/18505605-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>While watching the new movie SONYA I was struck by the level of grace and kindness displayed by a woman in a difficult situation.
The movie tells the story of Sonya, an orphaned teenager who lives in a work house because she has nowhere else to go. She is tormented by all the girls in the home. You would think that being in this situation day after day, year after year, it would harden her heart against the people that are ill treating her.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/32449011-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 18:36:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/32449011-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>I’ve always viewed life as a long string of adventures. Some have been big ones, like moving away from home when I was 18, starting a new job at a bank, getting married, having children and more recently, landing a regular place in a comedy show. Others have been smaller, but no less exciting, like going to the park on a sunny day or simply indulging my love of ice cream.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/50211668-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:41:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/50211668-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>In a world full of flux and change, progress is ever in motion. Technology-driven progress is often considered to be the greatest determinant of many of the challenges our world faces today. In this article, we examine the biblical perspective of technology as it relates to our views on progress. We consider a broad definition of progress before going on to focus more specifically on technological innovation. By drawing upon several biblical principles and patterns of thought from scripture, we explore the ways in which both the Giver and the Creator of everything we have can help us navigate what will otherwise remain as a challenging journey for as long as time itself lasts.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/68648165-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 08:21:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/68648165-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>The concept of "self" has been investigated and debated since its conception. In our daily lives, the word "self" is used constantly in many contexts. For example, I might say "I am a Christian" or "I am an American." However, the individual components of these statements are vague. When I use the words "self" and "me," I am using two completely different concepts. How does theology relate to the "self"? Can we, as Christians, have a "</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/99823364-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:55:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/99823364-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>14 Hear, O my people, all of you;
open your ears, and listen to me!
Should I not plead with you for your children,
should I not weep bitterly for those in the ranks of Israel?
My heart is struck down within me;
my hope was fragmented in my great anguish.
15 Will I let myself be moved away from these, my children?
Let my soul not hate these, my other children?</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/21983608-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 21:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/21983608-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>How you should view other Christians who are committed to the gospel and belong to a local church is pretty clear in the Bible. We're one people, "God's household," as Paul calls it in Ephesians 2:19, which means we're members of the same family. The Greek word translated into English as "household" here is oikos, which is the basis for the word "economics." It was a common term used by Paul to refer to Roman households, or oikoi.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/85971494-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 15:34:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/85971494-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>The term ‘fundamentalism’ was first used in 1920 to describe a set of beliefs in America. These beliefs were called the 5 fundamental doctrines of the Christian faith:
The inerrancy of Scripture; the virgin birth of Jesus Christ; the substitutionary atonement; the bodily resurrection of Jesus; the second coming of Jesus. Christian Fundamentalists are not simply committed to these doctrines, but they seek to defend them against criticism. Over time the term ‘fundamentalism’ has been applied to other religions, though the term is more commonly used to describe conservative Protestantism or sometimes Pentecostalism.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/52582827-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 23:41:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/52582827-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>Within a Christian framework, it is possible to envisage why Christians would emphasize Hell as a form of retribution for doing bad actions. However, one must understand that this is only an aspect of the way Christian theology explains the problem of sin and salvation within the larger framework of the Christian faith. Indeed, for some Christians, the stress on Hell may seem rather strong and strident, especially in light of Jesus’s message.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/24530013-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 12:49:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/24530013-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>One of the biggest hindrances for living the life we want to live is the guilt that still inhabits our psyche because of what we did in our past or what someone else did. In previous posts, I shared how I finally moved through some old guilt to a place where I've finally come to peace with it. The anger stage helped me to be more aware of my thoughts and habits as they related to it, and the forgiveness process allowed me to reach a place of peace about the past.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/36057570-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 13:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/36057570-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>In many ways, a generation of believers are losing their religion. A research conducted in 2016 among Christians in the US found that 32% of Christians under the age of 40 have become either agnostic or atheist.[1] Even among the remaining 68% who still hold to some belief in God, there is an alarming drop in numbers regarding their level of belief that God has to do anything with Christianity and its practices.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/33109596-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 18:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/33109596-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>A new convert may be a bit apprehensive about starting to follow Christ for the first time, and so might want a quick lesson or two on the basics. This is intended especially for those who aren't entirely familiar with what's expected of them in the early going, or what Jesus really has in mind for His followers. It will also serve as a handy refresher course for those of us who have been around the block a few times (or more).</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/39342586-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 10:07:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/39342586-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>Ever since I had been a young boy, I’d wondered what heaven is like. It is not to be seen in the physical sense of sight but must be perceived by the mind. This is especially true when we observe the different pictures that artists use to portray heaven and God. Once you accept this fact, it becomes easier to understand why there are so many ideas about heaven that are simply unbiblical.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/39498995-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:53:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vosaqobir.github.io/posts/39498995-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>Pastors can struggle in many areas of their lives – leadership, time management, shepherding God’s people. One area that is often overlooked, but can become a battlefield for pastoral ministry, is simply the asking and receiving of help.
Many people have something to offer you. But they will only offer if you ask.
I remember a conversation with my pastor when I was 17 years old. He told me that he could not do all he wanted to do alone – ministry is a team sport!</description></item></channel></rss>